deliaonline.com 2018-12-31

# Our Privacy and Cookie Policy | Delia Online

The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) replaces the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and was designed to harmonise data privacy laws across Europe, to protect and empower all EU citizens data privacy and to reshape the way organisations across the region approach data privacy.

To comply with new EU regulations, which come into force on May 25th 2018, Delia Online is legally required to contact _all_ members, including anyone who has been a member and subsequently unsubscribed, who in turn must actively give us permission to gather personal information. This information is the questions you are asked by us when you register to become a member, receive newsletters, enter competitions, or post on our Ask Lindsey page. Our data is stored in a secure database protected by a number of access controls. If you have opted-in when registering to receive third-party communications by email they will be from specially vetted companies who we feel may be able to supply you with products or services that add value to your experience with Delia Online. In these circumstances, any information you provide will be subject to the privacy policies of these companies. Data collected through the registration process or market research processes on the site will be used to improve the site, helping us to tailor our services to your needs. [**_If you want to know more about GDPR click here_**](https://www.eugdpr.org/)

We collect different types of information about our users for four main reasons:

**1.** To provide personalised services unique to our members, i.e. Shopping Lists, Your Favourite Recipes.

**2.** To help us to monitor and improve the services we offer.

**3.** To sell advertising space on the site, which helps us to keep the site free for people who visit it.

**4.** If we have permission from the user, or where otherwise allowed by law, to market services to them.

### PRIVACY

**1** We do our very best to protect your privacy by using security technology appropriately. This means:

• we make sure that we have appropriate security measures to protect your information; and

• we make sure that when we ask another organisation to provide a service for us, they have appropriate security measures.

**2** We will respect your privacy. You should only receive emails from us, and if you agree, from other organisations we have carefully chosen. We will make sure it is clear when you can make these choices, for example, we have boxes you need to tick if you want to receive marketing and you can change your preferences if you no longer want to receive it. However, we may email you occasionally with information or questions about your registration, your subscription account or postings

**3** We will collect and use member’s details only if we have your permission

**4** We will be clear in our dealings with you as to what information about you we will collect and how we will use it.

**5** We will use personal information only for the purposes for which it was originally collected and we will make sure we delete it securely.

### INFORMATION

We collect information on you:

• when you register as a member of Delia Online

• when you use the website

• through cookies

• if you choose to reveal information and/or add a photograph in postings on our Ask Lindsey pages

• when you enter sales promotions and competitions.

### REGISTRATION

Delia Online, may be visited and browsed by anyone in the world for free, however, to receive communications from us you will be required to register as a member.  Registration is for a single user only and the responsibility of any passwords rests with you. The minimum information required to register you is your name, town, postcode, gender, age bracket, email address, user name and a password. Unless we say otherwise, you have to answer all the registration questions.  **Why do we ask these questions?**   We ask for your name in order to personalise your newsletter; your town, postcode, gender and age bracket to specifically target 3rd party communications (which you only receive with your permission), for instance, an event may need to be targetted to a specific geographical area, a make-up range may be targeted to female members only, a retirement-based email may be targeted to a relevant age group. Your email address is to ensure you are a real person and not a robot; a password so that you can log in to your account. If you enter a competition we will ask you for a telephone number, this is so that we can contact winners directly.

**We will never, ever sell or share any of this information without your permission.**

After you have registered, and only with your permission, we may send you emails we think may interest you, ie. regular fortnightly newsletters, plus short newsletters, usually of seasonal content (Cake of the Week, Menu of the Month, Christmas emails). At any time you can decide not to receive these emails and will be able to ‘unsubscribe’. We have a ‘My details’ page where you can update your personal information at any time, and change your marketing preferences. You can get to this page by logging in and clicking on My Account. You will always be able to unsubscribe from the bottom of all our newsletters and communications.

It at any time you wish to see the personal information you have shared with us, you can do this via My details, and download a zip file, which contains a file with your data, and a picture file if you have shared a photograph with us.

**Right to be forgotten**  
At any time you can close your account, by visiting My Account in your profile.  All your details will be securely deleted.

**Use of children’s data**  
We are unable to approve membership to children under the age of 13.  Only children aged 13 or over are able to provide their own consent. This is the age proposed by the Data Protection Bill, and is subject to Parliamentary approval. We will update this notice should the situation change. 

**Who we share data with**  
We will not share your personal information with others for marketing purposes unless you have given us your permission, and then we will share your information only with other organisations we have chosen carefully. We may make other organisations’ services available, through our sites, although we are not necessarily operating these sites. We process any information, which we collect when you access a service provided by another organisation under this privacy policy. Information these other organisations collect is governed by their own privacy policies.

If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our members, or others.

**Sale or transfer of all or part of our business or assets**  
We reserve the right to transfer your personal information in the event we sell or transfer all or a part of our business or assets so that the buyer can continue to offer you the online services. We will make reasonable efforts to provide you with advance notification of the transfer of your information in such circumstances.

### COOKIES

**What is a cookie?** Rather than something you can eat, these cookies are small files of data, often incorporating a unique identifier. This is sent to your computer or mobile browser from a website's computer. This data file stores the information you provide us with and in doing so enables us to 'remember' you on repeat visits, effectively letting you move around the site without having to keep logging in. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but you can set your browser to prevent this. If your browser’s preferences allow it, each website or third party service provider is able to send a cookie to your browser. However, to protect your privacy, your browser only allows these websites or third party service providers to access cookies already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites or other third party service providers.  **Please note that cookies cannot harm your computer**.

Cookies record information about your online preferences, which are then used to tailor our website to your individual preferences. You can set your devices to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. However, if you choose the third option, please bear in mind that you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the features on Delia Online. Each browser is different; so check the [_**'Help' menu of your browser to find out how to change your cookie preferences.  **_](https://www.deliaonline.com/cookies-used-on-delia-online)

For more detailed information regarding cookies, types of cookies and how to manage cookies please see: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

**How does Delia Online use cookies?**  
 **1** For statistical purposes to track how many users we have and how often they visit our websites. We collect information listing which of our pages are most frequently visited, and by which types of users and from which countries.

**2** We use other organisations to collect anonymous user information, sometimes through cookies and web beacons, (information embedded in images which allow them to analyse how the website is being used and the number of visitors). When you interact with these services they may collect information from and about you and your interaction with their content. This activity will be subject to the privacy policy of and your settings for your chosen network. Please be aware that they may track your activity, through the use of cookies or similar technology, without you needing to interact with them. If this concerns you, ensure you log out of their services before using ours.

**3** We and other advertisers may use statistical cookies to track who has seen an advert and clicked on it. You can find more information on this in the online behavioural advertising section of this privacy policy.

**4** We may also share anonymous behavioural data with our advertising partners. This may mean that when you are on other websites, you will be shown advertising based on your behaviour on Delia Online, we may also show you advertising on our site based on your behaviour on other sites.

**5** We may use ‘Flash’ cookies to store your preferences for your media player (for example, volume and so on). If we don’t use them, you may not be able to watch some video content.

6 You can turn cookies off but if you do this, you may not be able to use all services on our websites and you might see more pop-ups and other advertising. This is because we won’t be able to limit what you see by using cookies. However, you will still be able to see our editorial content.

**7** We or other companies may use cookies to suggest and deliver content, which we believe, may interest you.

**8** Cookies are either session cookies (which are stored only for the duration of your visit to this website and these are deleted from your device when your browsing session ends) or may be persistent cookies and are saved on your device for a fixed period.  Persistent cookies are used where we need to know who you are for more than one usage session- for example, if you have asked us to remember preferences like your username.

By using the site you are agreeing to the use of cookies as described. _**[See all cookies used on Delia Online](https://www.deliaonline.com/cookies-used-on-delia-online)**_

**Google Analytics**  
We use Google Analytics on our site for anonymous reporting of site usage and for advertising on the site. If you would like to opt-out of Google Analytics monitoring your behaviour on our sites [_**please use this link**_](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

### ADVERTISING

An advertising service called online behavioural advertising (OBA), allows us to deliver targeted advertising to people who visit our website. It works by showing you adverts that are based on your browsing patterns and the way you have interacted with our site. It then shows you adverts, which we believe may interest you. As you browse our sites, some of the cookies we place on your computer will be advertising cookies, so we can understand what sort of pages you are interested in. We can then display advertising on your browser that is based on these perceived interests. For instance if you have been reading a lot of food and drink articles, you may be shown more adverts for food and drink. It is important to remember that none of the OBA techniques we use will collect information such as your name, email address or postal address

We may also share anonymous behavioural data with our advertising partners. This may mean that when you are on other websites, you will be shown advertising based on your behaviour on Delia Online, we may also show you advertising on our site based on your behaviour on other sites. Behavioural retargeting is another form of OBA that allows us and some of our advertising partners to show you ads based on your browsing patterns and interactions with a site away from our site. For example, if you have visited the website of an online clothes shop, you may start seeing ads from that same shopping site displaying special offers or showing you the products that you were browsing. This allows companies to advertise to you if you leave their website without making a purchase. If you want to opt out of receiving online behavioural advertising, this does not mean that you will no longer receive advertising when you are using our site. It just means that the advertising you see will not be customised for you.

Advertising on mobile devices may require the collection and sharing of the unique device ID with companies who purchase advertising space on the mobile application.

**Other Advertising**  
We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies please visit the [_**ICO's Cookies page**_](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/)

Our site contains links to other websites from which we may earn revenue. Our articles are never influenced by advertisers or affiliates, nor are they written for the purpose of promoting a product, except when clearly branded as ‘Advertisement Promotion’

**Legal information and how to contact us**  
If you have any questions or concerns, including use of disclosure of personal information, or breach of our Privacy Policy, please contact us and we will investigate.  We will treat your request or complaint confidentially and aim to resolve in a timely and appropriate manner.  Contact us at [enquiries@deliaonline.com](mailto:enquiries@deliaonline.com), or you may write to The Data Protection Officer Delia Online, PO Box 1124, Knaphill, Woking, GU21 9AA

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
Should we elect to change our privacy policy we will post the changes here. Where the changes are significant, we may also choose to email all our registered members with the new details. Where required by law, will we obtain your consent to make these changes.

Page updated on May 22nd 2018
